Draft day 2026, JP Shadrick with Jaguars
GM James Gladstone. Second draft as the
general manager. Take us through your
draft day routine. There's now a
routine. You've done this twice. You
know what, each of the last two cycles
it's looked a little different. So,
can't say that it's been the exact same
this year as it was a year ago today.
Can say that we're juiced up and jacked
about what lies in front of us with 11
at bats. There's been a lot of
preparation always leading up to a
draft, years in advance scouting, but
your scouting staff, your personnel
staff, the coaching staff,
a lot of people behind the scenes to
help you and this group get to a
decision. How about all the work that's
gone into this draft?
>> Undoubtedly, the collective effort to
date has been phenomenal. It's been
really cool to see just the connective
tissue built up over the last
year and really culminating in what will
be this weekend's efforts and getting a
chance to invite
you know, about a dozen guys into our
environment and the undrafted college
free agents afterwards
to help make this team better and really
move the needle forward. From your
conversations around the league, how
wild could the first round get tonight
in terms of movement up and back teams
and are the Jaguars in that conversation
as well? Yeah, you know, you never know
when
you know, things are going to pop off so
to speak and you hear the buzz around
certain windows especially in the first
round that it might get hot or it might
be cold and I think it's certainly going
to be energized there at the start and
could see a healthy lull there in the
middle and then you know, a lot of teams
there at the back end seem to be taking
some phone calls. Okay, they are taking
phone calls. So, you're making phone
calls. You know what, certainly doing
our part to at least engage in whatever
path may lie in front of us and what
avenues those could look like. James,
not your first rodeo without a first
round pick. Seven of the nine drafts you
were involved in in LA didn't have a
first round pick. One of them since the
first pick you had was in the third
round. So, looking ahead to day two and
three,
how does that experience help you in a
draft like this? Yeah, I think it plays
a significant role. Obviously, you know,
that time on task so to speak is going
to be a a heavy piece to the puzzle here
and you know, looking forward just in
the the collaboration that we've been
able to do and
you know, see that sort of picture paint
itself in real time and remain agile
knowing that you know, as it stands
right now, we got a a map of what it
could look like, but knowing we got to
stay on our feet and be able to react in
a way that's going to make this team
better moving into next year and beyond.
In general, what kind of prospect fits
the best in this Jaguars ecosystem? I
think it's pretty clear, JP. Intangibly
rich.
Got to look for that always. And looking
ahead now, what is a successful weekend
for the Jaguars? At the end of the day,
Saturday night, all the undrafted guys
are signed, everything's in the the
hay's in the barn so to speak. What is
success for the Jaguars? Yeah, I think
we're focused on adding the people that
we've identified as being
clear-cut fits within our environment
and knowing that those types will thrive
and meet whatever possible outcome they
can possibly get to if they're in our
our organization, on our team. And so,
ensuring that those are the guys that we
stick to and remain disciplined around.
I think that'll be something that
process
over results and and knowing that really
that'll be what shapes the future for us
and really looking forward to seeing
what this weekend holds, but knowing
that that's really where our minds will
be. Always a pleasure. Good luck to you
tonight and throughout the weekend. Game
on.